Merrimack Woolen Mills Photographs 6782 P
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Merrimack Woolen Mills Photographs
1940-1944
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Merrimack Woolen Mills
6782 P
1 folders
1 file folder
Photographs, gelatin silver print.
Photographs of Merrimack Woolen Mills construction and completed mill.
10063999
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
R. Miles, October 10, 2017
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, December 01, 2017
Scope and Contents
Photographs of Merrimack Woolen Mills construction and completed mill.
Includes images of land clearing, excavation, and construction for new mill in Dracut, Massachusetts. Also includes an image of skinner engine installed in the mill in 1944.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Textile factories; Woolen and worsted manufacture.; Textile factories -- Design and construction; Steam-engines; Skinner Engine Company; Franklin (N.H.); Franklin Falls (Franklin, N.H.); Franklin Mills (Franklin, N.H.); Merrimack River (N.H. and Mass.); Dracut (Mass.); Aero Scenic Airviews Co.; M.T. Stevens & Sons Co., Inc.; Merrimack Woolen Mills (Dracut, Mass.)
10063999
- Merrimack Woolen Mills construction, 1940-1944 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Item 1: Aerial view of Merrimack Woolen Mills, Dracut, Mass., black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents
    Gelatin silver print, [before 1940]. Image depicts the Merrimack Woolen Mills complex in Dracut, Mass., in the center of the photo; houses visible in lower foreground and upper background. The body of water is Beaver Brook; the complex sits at the lower falls of Beaver Brook. 25.25 x 20.5 cm.
    Format: black and white photograph.
  - Item 2: Excavation for new mill., 1940; black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Marion Photographers, Lowell, Mass. Gelatin silver print. Image depicts the excavation work for the new mill on March 21, 1940. Excavating equipment in the background. 24.5 x 19.5 cm.
  - Item 3: Test for foundation., 1940; black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Marion Photographers, Lowell, Mass. Gelatin silver print. Image depicts a wooden platform in an open area loaded with bags of sugar, apparently as a test for the foundation, March 21, 1940. Body of water (Beaver Brook?) seen in background. 24.5 x 19.5 cm.
  - Item 4: Excavation area cleared for new mill., 1940; black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Marion Photographers, Lowell, Mass. Gelatin silver print. Image depicts the cleared excavation area for the new mill, March 21, 1940. Body of water (Beaver Brook?) is seen in background, with houses on the far side of the pond/brook. 24.5 x 19.5 cm.
  - Item 5: View of construction, 1940; black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Marion Photographers, Lowell, Mass. Gelatin silver print. Image depicts a view of the ongoing construction of the new mill, May 21, 1940. Foundation has been laid; framework is beginning. Construction workers visible in middle ground and background; construction vehicle in background. See item 6 in this folder for a view of the same area from a different angle. 24.5 x 19.75 cm.
  - Item 6: View of construction., 1940; black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Marion Photographers, Lowell, Mass. Gelatin silver print. Image depicts a view of the ongoing construction of the new mill, May 21, 1940. Foundation has been laid; framework is beginning. Construction workers and vehicles visible in middle ground and background; houses in background. See item 5 in this folder for a view of the same area from a different angle. 24.5 x 19.75 cm.
  - Item 7: Engineering sighting in construction area., 1940; black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Marion Photographers, Lowell, Mass. Gelatin silver print. Image depicts a view of the ongoing construction of the new mill, May 21, 1940. A construction worker or engineer is taking a sighting in the middle of the foundation area. Construction workers visible at the top of the framework. 24.5 x 19.75 cm.
  - Item 8: New building completed., 1940; black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Marion Photographers, Lowell, Mass. Gelatin silver print. Image depicts a view of the completed new building of the Merrimack Woolen Mills, probably November 1940. Building is four-story multi-colored brick; reflected in pond in foreground. Written on reverse: "Merrimac Woolen Mill. Work started Thursday, February 29, 1940. Work finished November 1, 1940. R.S. Runnels, Lowell contractors." 24.5 x 19.5 cm.
  - Item 9: Skinner Steam Engine in Merrimack Woolen Mills, Dracut, Mass., 1944; black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Marion Photographers, Lowell, Mass. Gelatin silver prin. Image depicts a Skinner steam engine installed in the Merrimack Woolen Mills in Dracut, Mass. (owned by M.T. Stevens & Sons Co., Inc.). 25 x 20.25 cm.